Hillary N.M. Nthome

Email: hillarynthome97@gmail.com Tel: 0797259596 LinkedIn: LinkedIn

WEB DEVELOPER | GRAPHICS DESIGNER

Enthusiastic and self-motivated web developer and graphics designer with 3+ years of experience. Eager to join an Information technology firm and bring my skill in frontend development, and visual design to every project that will be received in the future. A previous project for airport transfer and taxi improved its customers and was able to reach many customers.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Programming / Codding

As a tech person I have gained experience in different programming languages, libraries and frameworks such as (Java, PHP, Python, Django, Node.js, React.js, Bootstrap, CSS, C#, C++, C, Kotlin, JavaScript, MySQL, SQL, ASP.Net) among others.

• Graphic designing

Interacted with various platforms such as Adobe photoshop, adobe illustrator, Canva, Figma hence improving my design skills.

Problem solving

learned techniques to solve problems and how to handle different problems and how to make decisions.

Strong organizational and time-management skills.

This is a skill I have taken into consideration in every aspect as being a web developer and working on projects require time and project management skills.

• Exceptional communication and interpersonal skills.

Communication is a key aspect in my day-to-day operations, I am able to interact well with others and clients via digital platforms (Google meets, MS teams, Webex) and also physically.

Ability to work independently and as part of a team.

Team work is key as collaboration makes work easier and

- Detail-oriented and able to handle multiple tasks simultaneously.
- Web development

I have done several projects for clients that have boosted their reach to customers and also sales.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ICT AUTHORITY Feb 2023 - Dec 2023

System And Applications Developer Intern.

Recruited as a system development intern at the ICT authority under the Presidential Digital Talent program (PDTP) to spearhead the governments ICT Programs such as the Jitume, e-waste management and also promote digital literacy to citizens.

Key contributions:

- Researched on e-waste collection, handling and management. This led to the establishment of the e-waste management center at the industrial area.
- Collaborated with other developers to design and produce the Product requirement document of the e-waste system. Which led to the development of the e-waste management system that manages all the devices collected those that have been tested.
- **Digital literacy training to youths and Citizens**. The Jitume program gave knowledge to citizens and enabled them learn how to work online and use the public WIFI installed by the government.
- Collaboration with other government ministries. Collaborated with the ministry of education where I worked as a Data capture for the Kenya National Examinations which boosted accuracy and completed the work in short period required.
- Attended trainings provided for Interns. Got different certifications and trainings from Coursera, Huawei, WEE center.

PETANNS TECHNICAL TRAINING COLLEGE

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

ICT Officer/ Trainer

Recruited to train students on computer applications, programming, secretarial studies and also perform staff support and maintenance. Also developed a small internal registration system to keep track of all the students and their information.

Key contributions

- Teaching practical skills. Taught many students and got many referrals as a good trainer.
- **Updating software and configurations.** The software where up to date and the machines where fast hence learning was smooth and interesting.
- **Graphics designing.** Impacted graphics skills to many students and also developed online cyber to offer services to clients.
- Improved number of students in the college. As a good trainer student referred other students and the this increased the number.

KENYA RED CROSS (MACHAKOS BRANCH)

MAY 2021- DEC 2021

ICT Intern

Roles and responsibilities:

- **Network administration and troubleshooting.** Made sure the network was running smoothly and assisted in doing configurations and solved connectivity issues.
- Facilitating Digital Opportunity trust (DOT) computer classes. Taught computer applications and life skills to many students.
- **Software and hardware support**. Made sure all the computers were functioning well and updated the software.
- **Staff support.** Aided the staff in matters that required my expertise
- Graphics design assisted in designing event/Blood donation posters and banners.

EDUCATION AND TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (Jan 2019 - Dec 2021)

Mount Kenya University Thika, Kenya

Diploma in Information Technology (Sep 2016 - Dec 2018)

Mount Kenya University Thika, Kenya

Technical skills:

Adobe photoshop, illustrator, CorelDraw, Canva, Figma, MS office, Microsoft suite, Operating systems (MS Windows (win 10,11,7,8.1), Linux, mac OS.